<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Zobaer Ahmed</title>
    <link>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zobaerahmed.us/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://zobaerahmed.us/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How far will Carbon Dioxide (CO2) Levels Rise in the Future?</title>
      <link>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/carbon-reseivor-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/carbon-reseivor-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>

















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-figure-1-a-sub-cycle-within-the-global-carbon-cycle-source-moffitts-farm-2020&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C5112AQFFoVSr-8BbhQ/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1520242339602?e=1615420800&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=Iwaajt5BwD2Kun2sv1XQK_ZUey5kTHqIYdu4bXfKdvg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Figure 1: A sub-cycle within the global carbon cycle; Source: Moffitts Farm, 2020&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C5112AQFFoVSr-8BbhQ/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1520242339602?e=1615420800&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=Iwaajt5BwD2Kun2sv1XQK_ZUey5kTHqIYdu4bXfKdvg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Figure 1: A sub-cycle within the global carbon cycle; Source: Moffitts Farm, 2020
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carbon is the building block of life. All living things are made mostly of carbon, oxygen, hydrogen,
nitrogen, calcium, and phosphorous. Among these, carbon acts as a binding material to form important compounds such as sugar, fat, and proteinswhich are necessary for the existence of life on
earth. Besides this, carbon is also present in the
earth&amp;rsquo;s atmosphere, soils, oceans, and crust. If
we consider our earth as a single system, then
these components which are also known as
carbon pools, stocks or reservoirs, acts as
storage houses for large amounts of carbon.
The movement of carbon between these carbon
pools is known as flux. In any integrated
system, fluxes together with carbon pools
create cycles and feedback. An example is seen
in (Figure 1) where, atmospheric carbon
dioxide is circulating and used in photosynthesis to create new plant material and eventually returns to the atmosphere.
On a global scale, this cycling process transfers huge amounts of carbon from one stock (e.g. the atmosphere) to another stock (e.g. plants). To complete this cycle, these plants die and decay, some of them are harvested by humans, or others are set fire either for energy or in wildfires. 
All these processes eventually cycle carbon among various pools within earth’s ecosystems and in times release it to the atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a very short period, plant communities take carbon from the earth’s atmosphere through a process
called photosynthesis and produce carbohydrate. Besides some carbon is incorporated into plant tissue and
then after using those carbon, they release it back into the atmosphere via an internal process called
respiration. In contrast, on a longer time scale, those carbon released from decayed plant materials can be
mixed into soils, where they reside for years or decades before released back to the atmosphere by the
process of soil microbial breakdown (decay). On a much longer time scale, past organic matter protected
from decay was slowly transformed into deposits of coal, oil and natural gas, combinedly known as the
fossil fuels that we use today for various purposes. By the process of burning fossil fuels, the carbon which
were stored for centuries is once again released back to the earth’s atmosphere in the form of carbon dioxide
(CO2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The carbon cycle has a large effect on the function and wellbeing of our planet. Globally, the carbon cycle
plays a key role in balancing the earth’s climate by managing the concentration of carbon dioxide in the
atmosphere. Carbon dioxide (CO2) gas is one of the main components which causes the greenhouse effect,
in which heat produced from sunlight is trapped by certain gases (including CO2) at earth’s surface. This
acts as a protective cover and prevents the heat from escaping through the atmosphere. From the very existence of the earth, greenhouse effect has played an important role by regulating earth’s surface
temperature naturally without human interference. Without it, the earth would be an extremely cold planet.
But in recent years, due to unnatural massive buildup of greenhouse gasses at earth’s surface as a result of
human action, we are experiencing unnaturally hot weather globally which is the result of greenhouse effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years CO2 has received much attention
because its concentration in the atmosphere has risen to
approximately 30% above natural background levels
and believed to continue to rise in the near future as
well. Many environmental scholars have shown in their
research that this increase is a result of human activities
that have occurred over the last 150 years, including the
unregulated burning of fossil fuels and deforestation.
As we know that CO2 is a greenhouse gas, this increase
is believed to be causing a rise in global temperatures.
This is the primary cause of climate change and is the
main reason for increasing interest in the carbon cycle
(Figure 2).&lt;/p&gt;


















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-figure-2-the-carbon-cycle-and-simple-mechanism&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C5112AQE-IKgQJJoldA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1520042030252?e=1615420800&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=VPqWD8byNUz4zhVKfqO9DErvA-rBsn3WSZoLYbDJXAM&#34; data-caption=&#34;Figure 2: The Carbon Cycle and Simple Mechanism&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://media-exp1.licdn.com/dms/image/C5112AQE-IKgQJJoldA/article-inline_image-shrink_1000_1488/0/1520042030252?e=1615420800&amp;amp;v=beta&amp;amp;t=VPqWD8byNUz4zhVKfqO9DErvA-rBsn3WSZoLYbDJXAM&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Figure 2: The Carbon Cycle and Simple Mechanism
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The earth’s carbon stocks naturally act as both sources: adding carbon to the atmosphere, and sinks:
removing carbon from the atmosphere. If all sources are equal to all sinks, the carbon cycle can be said to
be in equilibrium (or in balance) and there is no change in the size of the pools over time. Maintaining a
steady amount of CO2 in the atmosphere helps maintain stable average temperatures at the global scale.
However, because fossil fuel combustion and deforestation have increased CO2 inputs to the atmosphere
without matching increases in the natural sinks that draw CO2 out of the atmosphere (oceans, forests, etc.),
these activities have caused the size of the atmospheric carbon pool to increase. This is what has been
responsible for the present buildup of CO2 and is believed to cause the observed trend of increasing global
temperatures. Now the question is, how far will CO2 levels rise in the future? The answer depends both on
how much CO2 humans continue to release and on the future amount of carbon uptake and storage by the
earth&amp;rsquo;s natural sinks and reservoirs. In short, we can say that it depends on the carbon cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Wowchemy, the website builder for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zobaerahmed.us/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Wowchemy website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong&gt;no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong&gt; and having &lt;strong&gt;flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


















&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/templates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Wowchemy community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%28%23MadeWithWowchemy%20OR%20%23MadeWithAcademic%29&amp;amp;src=typed_query&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomplans&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-admin/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy Admin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; An admin tool to automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
